<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="www.kimmj.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="www.kimmj.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-05-12T23:35:11+00:00</updated><id>www.kimmj.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Min Jae Kim</title><subtitle>Software Developer Portfolio</subtitle><author><name>Min Jae Kim</name></author><entry><title type="html">Coveo for Sitecore 4.1 (Hive) Certification Process</title><link href="www.kimmj.com/code/certification/coveo-for-sitecore-4-1-hive-certification-process/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Coveo for Sitecore 4.1 (Hive) Certification Process" /><published>2019-03-12T04:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-12T04:00:00+00:00</updated><id>www.kimmj.com/code/certification/coveo-for-sitecore-4-1-hive-certification-process</id><content type="html" xml:base="www.kimmj.com/code/certification/coveo-for-sitecore-4-1-hive-certification-process/">&lt;p&gt;I recently wrote the Coveo for Sitecore 4.1 (Hive) Certification exam and I would like to share my experience!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coveo for Sitecore is the most advanced search engine for Sitecore. Although Coveo supports both on-premise and cloud indexing, Coveo is moving closer towards the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step is to enrol in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://academy.coveo.com/series/coveo-for-sitecore-administrator-learning-path/coveo-for-sitecore-developer&quot;&gt;Coveo for Sitecore Developer Course&lt;/a&gt;. The course includes one free exam, and any retake costs 500 USD. If you or your employer is a Coveo solutions partner, you may be eligible to take this course for free, including the exam!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To take the most out of the Coveo training experience, I strongly recommend you take the online (pre-recorded) course twice. Make sure you can replicate all the labs without peeking at the solution manual or video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, the exam was tough. You will have 180 minutes for 90 questions unless you have a Coveo for Sitecore 3.0 Certification. That’s 1 question every 2 minutes! The entire exam is comprised of multiple choice questions, but many questions have multiple correct answers and you have to pick all the correct answers. Although you can pause the exam and come back later, you cannot go back to any of the previous questions. Coveo recommends that you do it in one sitting and I recommend the same as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the exam, you will be able to access the internet and any study materials, including the training PDF and the course videos. Make sure you save the PDF downloaded and have it handy at all times so you can search for specific keywords!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also recommend you prepare a Sitecore installation with the solution from the end of the Coveo training lab. If you don’t remember how some part was done during the exam, you can refer back to your Sitecore solution and try it out for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, have the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.coveo.com/en/2709/root/coveo-for-sitecore-documentation&quot;&gt;Coveo for Sitecore documentation&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coveo.com/en/login&quot;&gt;Coveo Cloud control panel&lt;/a&gt; open at all times. Searching the documentation and the control panel is crucial for this exam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good Luck!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Coveo_Min-Jae-Kim.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Min Jae Kim</name></author><category term="coveo" /><category term="certification" /><category term="sitecore" /><category term="coveo hive" /><category term="exam" /><category term="training" /><summary type="html">How I became a Coveo for Sitecore 4.1 Certified Developer!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sitecore 9.0 Certification Exam and Preparation</title><link href="www.kimmj.com/code/sitecore-9-0-certification-exam-and-preparation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sitecore 9.0 Certification Exam and Preparation" /><published>2018-06-30T04:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-30T04:00:00+00:00</updated><id>www.kimmj.com/code/sitecore-9-0-certification-exam-and-preparation</id><content type="html" xml:base="www.kimmj.com/code/sitecore-9-0-certification-exam-and-preparation/">&lt;p&gt;Sitecore is a web content management system (CMS) with extensive marketing and personalization features. With enterprise-grade websites like &lt;a href=&quot;http://pg.com&quot;&gt;Procter &amp;amp; Gamble&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;Huawei.com&quot;&gt;Huawei&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;lastpass.com&quot;&gt;LastPass&lt;/a&gt;, and many more, Sitecore is a valuable technology to learn as a web or full-stack developer. I received a great opportunity to study and write the Sitecore® 9.0 Certified Platform Associate Developer Exam, thanks to my employer &lt;a href=&quot;apiqu.com&quot;&gt;Apiqu&lt;/a&gt;. I recently passed the exam and I would like to share my experience studying for it, as well as some tips and tricks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, you need to take the Sitecore Developer courses provided to you by sitecore. You should visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://elearning.sitecore.net&quot; title=&quot;https://elearning.sitecore.net&quot;&gt;https://elearning.sitecore.net&lt;/a&gt; to take two of the following courses:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://elearning.sitecore.net/Public/ContentDetails.aspx?id=4D65DA79A42744A59B68DAF2895770BE&quot; title=&quot;Sitecore Developer Foundation 9.0&quot;&gt;Sitecore® Developer Foundation 9.0&lt;/a&gt; ($0)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://elearning.sitecore.net/Public/ContentDetails.aspx?id=BC286B8A482C49BD8CB52CE507B666D0&quot; title=&quot;Sitecore Experience Platform Essentials for Developers 9.0&quot;&gt;Sitecore® Experience Platform™ Essentials for Developers 9.0&lt;/a&gt; ($1500)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your employer is a Sitecore partner, you may be eligible for a discount (or even get it for free), so make sure you check before you buy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need to get 80% or higher to pass. I know! It’s fairly high!! This means that you need to get 40 out of 50 questions to pass the Sitecore Certification Exam. The exam is $300 (USD) and if you fail, you will have to pay for the exam again!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Sitecore, there are two ways to take the exam. Online, and offline testing centre. I (and probably 99% of other people) took the online exam, which is proctored. You need a separate webcam (not the one built into your laptop or monitor) and an empty desk (other than monitor/laptop, keyboard, and mouse) in order to do take the online exam. Don’t forget that no study aids are allowed (ie. no cheat sheets!) and you have 90 minutes to finish the exam. You can mark any question “I’m not sure” and come back at the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some sections are tested more than others, so refer to the exam competencies table below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Competencies&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;% of Questions&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;API&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;5 %&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Architecture&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;4 %&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Creating and Editing Items&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;8 %&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Development Environment&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;9 %&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Fields and Field Types&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;13 %&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Installation&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1 %&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Media&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1 %&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Module Packages&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1 %&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Presentation&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;18 %&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Publishing&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2 %&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Search&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;11 %&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Sitecore Documentation and Support&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1 %&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Templates&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;19 %&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Versioning&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2 %&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;xManagement&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;5 %&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;TOTAL&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;100%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of study materials online, so I encourage you to search Google. You will likely find the Sitecore Exam Study Guide on Sitecore’s freshdesk site, which is super useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Study materials used to study for my exam are included in the list below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://elearning.sitecore.net&quot; title=&quot;https://elearning.sitecore.net&quot;&gt;https://elearning.sitecore.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.sitecore.com/developers/90/index.html&quot; title=&quot;https://doc.sitecore.com/developers/90/index.html&quot;&gt;https://doc.sitecore.com/developers/90/index.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sitecore.freshdesk.com/support/solutions/articles/16000067853-sitecore-9-0-certified-platform-associate-developer-exam-study-guide-&quot;&gt;Sitecore® 9.0 Certified Platform Associate Developer Exam Study Guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My overall experience was great since their eLearning courses were well organized, although I think their eLearning web interface needs some fix. I was somewhat disappointed to learn that the certification expires. Mine expires on December 31st, 2020. If you are able to memorize everything in the eLearning course, you should be fine!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good luck!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/0001.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Min Jae Kim</name></author><category term="sitecore" /><category term="certification" /><category term="exam" /><category term="preparation" /><category term="developer" /><summary type="html">How I became a Sitecore 9.0 Certified Developer!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sitecore Hackathon 2019 with Apiqu!</title><link href="www.kimmj.com/code/sitecore-hackathon-2019-with-apiqu/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sitecore Hackathon 2019 with Apiqu!" /><published>2018-03-02T08:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-02T08:00:00+00:00</updated><id>www.kimmj.com/code/sitecore-hackathon-2019-with-apiqu</id><content type="html" xml:base="www.kimmj.com/code/sitecore-hackathon-2019-with-apiqu/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/sitecore-hackathon-grouppic.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sitecorehackathon.org/sitecore-hackathon-2019/&quot;&gt;Sitecore Hackathon Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Sitecore-Hackathon/2019-The-Knights-Who-Say-Ni&quot;&gt;Our Hackathon Submission&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Min Jae Kim</name></author><category term="Sitecore" /><category term="Hackathon" /><category term="SEO" /><category term="Sitecore Addon" /><category term="Marketing" /><category term="Content Editing" /><category term="CPC" /><summary type="html">Let's Take Some Picture!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Android Camera2 API Pipeline Manipulation</title><link href="www.kimmj.com/code/android-camera2-api-pipeline-app/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Android Camera2 API Pipeline Manipulation" /><published>2016-08-27T08:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-08-27T08:00:00+00:00</updated><id>www.kimmj.com/code/android-camera2-api-pipeline-app</id><content type="html" xml:base="www.kimmj.com/code/android-camera2-api-pipeline-app/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever since the birth of digital cameras, the ability to edit its image
processing pipeline has been held exclusively by the camera manufacturers.
Google is trying to change the game with the release of the Camera 2 API for
Android. This new program interface will enable developers to input functions
into the digital imaging pipeline (Figure 1) to customize and edit features.
Just like how we have phones which are 100 million times faster than the Apollo
11’s command module, the digital imaging pipeline can be altered on our phones,
once exclusively done by bulky and expensive hardware!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made an application which runs a user customizable pipeline based on Hakki Can
Karaimer’s publication[1] (https://karaimer.github.io/camera-pipeline/). The
main objective of this project was to normalize (calibrate) different cameras by
calculating the optimal RGGB Channel Vector. Proprietary pipelines built by
different phone manufacturers often produced different images under identical
scenes, but by calibrating the pipeline, I was able to produce identical images.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog/2016-08-27-android-camera2-api-pipeline-app/media/7e8d87d13c6ea7c1300e0c6a9c360cb6.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Figure 1 Karaimer H.C., Brown M.S. (2016) “A Software Platform for Manipulating
the Camera Imaging Pipeline”, European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV`16),
Oct 2016 (https://karaimer.github.io/camera-pipeline/)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;digital-imaging-pipeline&quot;&gt;Digital Imaging Pipeline&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As represented in Figure 1, the Digital Imaging Pipeline is split into 12
different steps; each step represents a function applied to the RAW image. I
focused on step 1, 2, 4, and 6 for my app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;reading-raw-image&quot;&gt;Reading Raw Image&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After raw data is taken in by the camera sensor, the electronic signals are
converted into a grayscale image with a Bayer pattern.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;black-light-subtraction&quot;&gt;Black Light Subtraction&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Black light subtraction is a method of brightening an image by reducing the
intensity of the black level. A black level is defined as the level of
brightness at the darkest part of the image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;demosaicing&quot;&gt;Demosaicing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually, in the form of Red Green Green Blue, the Bayer pattern must go through
a process called demosaicing before being processed further. This is represented
by Stage 4 of the pipeline and requires the green pixels in a four by four
matrix to be measured and averaged out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used OpenCV to accomplish this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog/2016-08-27-android-camera2-api-pipeline-app/media/dcdf0db1069713d9022b811534a3d21d.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Figure 2 Use this image to show demosaicing &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ok.sc.e.titech.ac.jp/\~ymonno/researches.html&quot;&gt;http://www.ok.sc.e.titech.ac.jp/~ymonno/researches.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;white-balancing&quot;&gt;White Balancing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The user selects the white area and the app calculates the RGGB Vector value
required to make the selected region white. This value is applied to the entire
RAW image to white balance. This process forces the selected region to have
identical Red, Green, and Blue pixels values.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog/2016-08-27-android-camera2-api-pipeline-app/media/7c5c7e3f3d7b851ddde7ec1d0bc2b756.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Figure 3 Raw Image with gamma correction (Left/Stage 1), Black Light
Substraction (Middle/Stage 2), White Balance (Right/Stage 6)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;other-abilities&quot;&gt;Other Abilities&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Auto Focus&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Manual Focus&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Preset White Balance Profiles&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Manual White Balance (User selects white area)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Preset Scene Modes&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Raw capture&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Manual ISO&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Manual Shutter Speed&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Intervalometer (Supports RAW)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Manual Colour Transformation Matrix&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;applications&quot;&gt;Applications&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Computer Vision:&lt;/strong&gt; This default process isn’t always preferred for uses in
computer vision or medical imaging. It is particularly important in computer
vision where it is extremely crucial for objects to be recognized, identified,
and properly labelled. An image ran through a typical pipeline can be mildly
useful for computer vision, but with pipeline manipulation, the chances of
recognition are greatly increased. For example, an object that blends in with
the environment can be recognized easier if the Tone Curve Application (Step 10)
of the pipeline can be altered to contrast the differences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Medical Imaging:&lt;/strong&gt; Along the same lines of computer vision, medical imaging
can benefit greatly from pattern recognition. According to “Spectral Response of
Silicon Image Sensors” by Arnaud Darmont April 2009, CMOS sensors typically
found in our phones can actually see higher and lower wavelengths than the human
eyes. By omitting or altering the typical imaging pipeline, we may be able to
use various silicon-sensitive wavelengths to diagnose illnesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aesthetic Photography:&lt;/strong&gt; Post-shoot photograph manipulation has been around
for years but unfortunately it has been accessible to very few people. Many
applications nowadays are able to manipulate photos by adding filters or
mechanisms to make them look more appealing or by editing RAW files in
post-shoot. As it turns out, the most popular filters occur naturally in nature
and can be easily found by simply removing or altering a step in the pipeline.
For example, Natural Vignetting; In step 3 of the pipeline, light (or the lack
thereof) is automatically compensated for through lens correction. Due to
smartphones having a low aperture, this step typically adds exposure to the
edges of the photo to match the exposure in the centre. Unknowingly to many of
the people posting Instagram pictures, the vignette does not require post-shoot
alterations, it only needs to be omitted by the pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;acknowledgements&quot;&gt;Acknowledgements&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project would have been impossible without the expert knowledge of Michael
S. Brown, Hakki Can Karaimer, and Abdelrahman Kamel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would also like to thank the Lassonde School of Engineering at York University
by letting me present this project at the Lassonde Research Conference with the
Lassonde Undergraduate Research Award.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Min Jae Kim</name></author><category term="Android" /><category term="Camera" /><category term="OpenCV" /><category term="Computer Vision" /><category term="White Balance" /><summary type="html">Let's Take Some Picture!</summary></entry></feed>